- 喂? - 喂
Hello? Hello.
- 请说? - 你是谁?
Yes? -Who is this?
- 你要找谁? - 你叫什么名字?
Who are you calling? -Who am l speaking to?
你打错了
Wrong number.
- 谁打来的? - 打错电话的
Who was that? Nobody.
你有租片子吗?
Did you pick a movie? Yeah.
有啊,租了恐怖片
We're gonna go scary.
"夺魂锯4"
Saw 4.
我去电影院看了,逊毙了
Ugh, l saw that in theaters. lt sucks.
完全不恐怖但很恶心
lt's not scary, it's gross.
我最讨厌变态虐杀片了
l hate all that torture porn shit.
你有什么感想?
How do you really feel?
拼图杀人魔很酷
Well, l like Jigsaw.
他杀人手法还蛮有创意的
l think he kills people very creatively.
谁死根本没差
But you don't give a shit who dies
没几个角色能活到下一集
'cause there's no character development.
只会断手断脚到处喷血
There's just body parts ripping and blood spewing.
你在传简讯给谁啊?
Who do you keep texting?
有人在脸书上骚扰我
l have a Facebook stalker.
一直留言给我
He keeps leaving me messages.
是喔,写些什么?
Yeah, like what?
像是"嘿,美女"
Just stuff. Like, " Hey, what's up.
"你好辣,我好想杀你"
You're hot. l wanna kill you."
删掉他吧
So delete him.
我删了,但他就是能留言
l did, but he hacked his way back in.
去检举他
So report him.
不过他真的很帅
He's really hot, though.
你要不要看看?
You wanna see?
那是查宁塔图
That's Channing Tatum.
才不是,真的吗?
lt is not. ls it?
对,这是他还是小模时的照片
Yeah, from his Abercrombie days.
你被耍了
You are being punked.
- 喂? - 你是谁?
Hello? Who is this?
刚才被你惹毛的那位
The more impatient version of the person you just spoke to.
抱歉,但你讲话不用这么呛
l'm sorry. You don't have to be a bitch about it.
不爽就来找我啊
Of course l don't . Eat me.
敢挂电话我就把你碎尸万段!
You hang up on me and l'll cut through your neck until l feel bone!
谁打来的?
Who is it?
找你的
lt's for you.
- 喂? - 你是谁?
Hello? -Who's this?
我是楚蒂,你是哪位?
lt's Trudie. Who's this?
我是来帮你收尸的人
This is the last person you're ever gonna see alive.
是骚扰电话,快挂掉
lt's a prank. Hang up.
干嘛把电话给我?
Why'd you hand the phone to me?
被骚扰的人是你
You're the one with the stalker.
- 门都锁了吗? - 别自己吓自己
Are the doors locked? Don't freak out.
不要接
Let it ring.
那个变态留言了
lt's from stalker boy.
他说"给我接电话"
He said, "Answer the phone."
别傻了,只是恶作剧
For God's sake. lt's a joke, Trudie.
搞不好是莱希或凯伦
lt's probably Lexi or Karen.
你要去哪?
Where are you going?
去检查大门锁了没
To make sure the front door is locked.
不要,别开门
No. Don't open it.
别胡思乱想
You're overreacting.
只是恶作剧,了吗?
lt's a joke, Trudie, okay?
有人申请假帐号来吓唬你
Somebody made a dummy profile. They're just trying to scare you.
等等…是谁?
Wait! Who is it?
我说…你是谁?
l said, who is it?
我们报警吧
Let's call the cops.
"我赌你不敢开门"
"l dare you to open the door."
不要,雪莉,别开门
No, Sherrie. Don't .
别开门,我好怕
No, don't , l'm scared.
可能是我们认识的人
Hey, it could be anyone that we know.
莉莎、贝利、韦恩…
Lisa, Bailey, Wayne...
也搞不好是查宁塔图
...or the hopeful long shot, Channing Tatum.
外面没有人
There's nobody out here.
他说什么?
What does it say?
他说"我不在外面"
lt says, " l'm not outside.
"我在你身边"
l'm right beside you."
楚蒂!
Trudie!
"刺杀6"
实在是有够瞎
You're fucking kidding me.
什么?
What?
超白烂的,乱拍一通
That was so fucking stupid. Pure horseshit.
恐怖片就快要灭亡了
The death of horror, right here in front of us.
我倒是被吓到了
l jumped. lt scared me.
脸书杀手吗?
A fucking Facebook killer?
你在开玩笑吧?
You're kidding me, right?
应该要叫推特杀手
l guess now it would be Twitter.
起码比较合理
That'd make more sense.
一堆青少年在分析恐怖电影
A bunch of articulate teens sit around and deconstruct horror movies...
然后分别被鬼面杀手干掉
until Ghostface kills them one by one.
这招早就玩烂了
lt's been done to death.
全是些没内容的老梗
The whole selfaware, postmodern meta shit.
1996年的电影早就过时了
Stick a fork in 1996, already.
我很喜欢"刺杀"
l like the Stab movies.
因为比较可怕
They're scarier.
因为不是外星人或僵尸
lt's not aliens or zombies
也不是东方女鬼
or little Asian ghost girls.
用刀的杀手比较有真实感
There's something real about a guy with a knife
比较…
who just...
惊悚
...snaps.
也可能真的会发生
lt could really happen.
我办不到
l can't do it.
续集不停地拍
These sequels don't know when to stop.
全部都是老梗新用
They just keep recycling the same shit!
每次开始都有某个女孩…
Even the opening scene. There's always some random girl...
接了电话然后就被杀了
who gets a call that undoubtedly ends up getting her killed.
白痴都猜得到
lt's all so predictable,
根本无法让人吓一跳
there's no element of surprise.
剧情全都猜得到
You can see everything coming.
这有吓到你了吧?
Did that surprise you?
为什么?
Why?
因为你话太多了
Because you talk too much.
给我闭嘴好好看电影吧
Now shut the fuck up and watch the movie.
"刺杀7"
天啊,我爱死了
Oh, my God, l love it.
我看了五次
l've seen it five times
每次都还会被吓到
and it still gets me every time.
少唬我了,我看不懂
You're kidding. l don't get it.
好吧
Okay.
- 就像"阴阳魔界" - 阴阳魔界?
lt's like The Twilight Zone. Twilight Zone?
- 就是戏中有戏 - 这我懂
A movie within a movie.
只是不合逻辑
l get that. But it's illogical.
如果7和6的开头一样
lt begs the question that if the beginning of Stab 7 is Stab 6...
那6跟5也一样?
...then is the beginning of Stab 6 Stab 5?
那么第4集在演什么?
And, if so, what is Stab 4 about?
你想太多了
You're overthinking it.
有吗?还是拍的人想太少了?
Am l? Or did whoever make it just underthink it?
所以我不爱看这种片
There's a reason l don't watch these movies.
真不敢相信你没看过
l can't believe you haven't seen them.
我们可是住在伍兹伯勒
We live in Woodsboro.
这跟住哪里无关
That has nothing to do with Woodsboro.
你说过"刺杀"改编自真实故事
l thought you said Stab was based on true stories.
前三集是拍席妮的故事
The first three, the original trilogy, is based off of Sidney Prescott...
但她说如果再拍就要提告
but then she threatened to sue them if they used her story...
所以片商只能乱掰了
so then they just started making stuff up.
第5集还穿越时光,扯毙了
Stab 5 has time travel, which is by far the worst.
我们每年都听也听够了吧?
Don't we hear enough about this story every year?
起码伍兹伯勒因此出名了
At least Woodsboro's known for something.
你有听到吗?
Did you hear that?
我什么都没听到
No, l didn't hear anything.
我有听到
l did.
珍妮,不要吓我
Jenny, don't try to scare me.
我没有要吓你
l'm not trying to scare you.
你每次都吓我
You do it all the time.
我才没有
No, l don't .
你要去哪?
Where are you going?
我真的有听到声音
l told you, l heard something.
你只是想吓我
l know you're trying to scare me.
我没有
l'm not.
怎么了?
What is it?
我大概忘了关卧房的窗户
l must have left a window in my room open.
接一下电话好吗?
Could you get that?
- 玛妮? - 好
Marnie? -Yeah.
- 喂? - 你是谁?
Hello? Hello. Who is this?
我是玛妮,你呢?
Marnie. Who's this?
我是来帮你收尸的人
This is the last person you're ever gonna see alive.
什么?
What?
真抱歉,我就是忍不住
l'm sorry. l had to.
臭婊子
You bitch.
一点都不好笑
So not funny.
每次都有人上当
Somebody falls for it every year.
我真不懂你的心态
l don't see why you get off on this...
玛妮?
Marnie?
真聪明,玛妮
Good one, Marnie.
灯关了,电话还扔地上
Lights out, phone on the floor.
你真应该当恐怖片导演的
You know, you really should direct horror films.
我来找你罗
Wherever you are.
让我猜猜
Let me guess.
你想等我走到门边
You want me to walk by an open doorfrrame...
然后出来吓我,是吗?
so you can pop out, huh?
好吧,时间抓得很准
Okay. Timing, timing is perfrect.
但你的手机没变声软件
But you don't have the app on your phone...
所以不能学鬼面杀手讲话
...so you can't talk like Ghostface...
- 对吧? - 我当然可以
...can you? Yes l can.
- 你是谁? - 我可不是软件
Who is this? Not an app.
是崔佛吗?
ls this Trevor?
我听起来像崔佛吗?
Do l sound like a Trevor to...
当我是导演好了
Think of me as your director.
你在拍我的电影
You're in my movie.
别把你的戏搞砸了
You got a fun part, so don't blow it.
什么电影?
What movie?
跟玛妮的一样
Same one Marnie's in.
只是她先杀青了
Only her part got cut way back.
至于你呢?
But you,
你是没脑的金发大奶妹
you're the dumb blonde with the big tits.
咱们先玩玩再让你死
We'll have some fun with you before you die.
我的学科满分、智商135,混蛋
l have a 4.0 GPA and a 135 lQ, asshole.
你把玛妮怎么了?
What did you do with Marnie?
- 她正躺在剪辑室的地上 - 不好笑
She's on the cutting room floor. That's not funny.
这不是喜剧,是恐怖片
This isn't a comedy. lt's a horror film.
有人幸存,有人死亡
People live, people die.
你最好赶快逃
And you'd better start running.
玛妮?
Marnie?
惊声尖叫4
你觉得如何?
What do you think?
纪念日又到了吧
Well, l guess today is the anniversary.
真幼稚
Kids.
我是说海报
No, l meant the display.
"重返光明"
"作者席妮皮斯考克"
"下午一点"
还不错
lt's good.
老板再不搞定就杀了他的猫
l told the owner l'd kill his cat if he didn't get it right.
厉害
Nice.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
开慢点,安全第一!
25, stay alive!
惨了!
Shit!
抱歉,警长!
Sorry, Sheriff!
臭可碧
Kirby.
上车前先答应我不能杀我
Hey, before you get in the car, you have to promise not to kill me.
为什么?你做了什么?
Why? What did you do?
崔佛昨晚有打给我
Trevor called me last night.
他打给你干嘛?
Why is he calling you?
因为你不接电话
Because you won't take his calls.
所以他找你的麻吉探口风
He knows l have your ear and he wants to know.
- 什么口风? - 问你有多气他
Know what? How upset you are.
我们先别聊这个好吗?
Look, can we just not talk about this now, please?
好…
Fine. Fine.
崔佛昨晚有打给我
Okay, so Trevor called me last night.
他也打给你?
He called you, too?
他担心你的表姊一来
He's worried your cousin coming to Woodsboro...
你就不去想原谅他的事了
...is distracting you from knowing how sorry he really is.
- 还真会乱掰 - 拜托
Well, that's inventive. Oh, God.
对了,你见到死神了吗?
By the way, have you seen the Grim Reaper?
死亡天使?
Angel of Death?
你在讲什么啊?
What are you talking about?
你表姊,席妮皮斯考克
Your cousin.
新书发表会的最后一站 新人生的第一站
Last stop on her book tour, first stop on her road to a new life.
还蛮戏剧性的
lt's very dramatic.
因为她我才爱上恐怖片的
She's the reason why l love horror movies.
她听到一定很高兴
l'm sure she'd love to hear that.
虽然我从没见过她
lf l knew her, which l don't really.
她所到之处都有人死
Wherever she went, people died.
全是别人,她都没事
Other people. lt was never her.
我觉得"刺杀"不适合她
l mean, Stab is the wrong franchise for her.
"绝命终结站"比较适合
lt should be Final Destination.
珍妮兰道打给我干嘛?
Okay, why is Jenny Randall calling me?
- 真受不了珍妮 - 喂?
l cannot stand Jenny. Hello?
嗨,吉儿
Hello, Jill.
珍妮?是你吗?
Jenny? ls this you?
你最喜欢的恐怖片是哪部?
What's your favorite scary movie?
够了,你是谁?
Okay, who is this?
她想干嘛?
What does she want?
你到底是谁?
l said, who is this?
我在问你问题
l asked you a question.
你最喜欢的恐怖片是哪部?
What's your favorite scary movie?
我要挂电话了
l'm hanging up.
真没创意
Wow. That was original.
玛妮早上才打来闹过我
l got a call like that this morning from Marnie the Carny.
- 什么? - 小心!
What? -Watch out!
你刚才忘了先停下来一下
You just ran a stop sign.
抱歉
Sorry.
死亡天使
The Angel of Death.
市长要求中午前把这些蠢东西拿掉
The mayor wants these down before lunch.
还剩25个
Only twentyfive more to go.
早安,警长
Morning, Sheriff.
早安,警员
Morning, Deputy.
乔
Joe.
早安,警长
-Morning, Sheriff.
他们又要开始庆祝了
Looks like the celebration's begun.
- 大概高中生搞的 - 是啊
High school kids, probably. Yeah.
上个世代的悲剧
One generation's tragedy
竟然是下个世代眼中的笑话
is the next one's joke.
抱歉,这是避免不了的
Sorry you can never get away from this.
其实我从小就想当警察
You know, l wish l'd been old enough to be part of the force
是因为受到了你的影响
when you were solving those crimes.
日以继夜的调查使大家团结
lt's those intense investigations that really bond relationships.
Well, yeah.
盖儿还好吗?
How is Gale, by the way?
还不错,目前在写作
Gale's good, she's writing.
小说
Fiction.
我做了柠檬蛋糕,我去车上拿
Hey, l made some lemon squares. They're in my car.
谢谢,不过不用了
Thanks, Deputy, but no thanks.
警长…
Sheriff...
吃我的蛋糕又不代表你劈腿
you're not cheating on your wife if you eat my lemon square.
对,但会背叛我的减肥计划
Yeah, but l would be cheating on my diet.
瑞利警长?请回答,瑞利警长!
Sheriff Riley? Come in, Sheriff Riley!
我是瑞利,请说
This is Sheriff Riley. Go ahead.
请火速赶往兰道家
You gotta get over to the Randall house right away.
情况很糟,非常严重
lt's bad, Sheriff, real bad.
这本书叫"重返光明"
The book is Out of Darkness
作者席妮皮斯考克
and its author, Sidney Prescott...
今天来到了现场
...is here with us today.
"刺杀"系列的剧本
Have the seven Stab movies,
都以你盖儿作为主角
all based on Gale Weathers‘ books about you...
你会因此备受挫折吗?
made it even harder to go on?
我不怪她,事情都过去了
l don't blame Gale. That's in the past.
如果我是长期的受害者
lf l was a victim for too long,
我必须靠自己重新振作
it was up to me to reinvent myself.
因此我才写了这本书
That's why l wrote this book.
席妮皮斯考克,各位观众
Sidney Prescott, everybody.
请热烈支持"重返光明"
And rave reviews for her book... Out of Darkness.
好了,盖儿,开工了
All right, Gale, let's do it.
重新振作起来
Let's reinvent myself.
Except...
我不知该他妈的如何…起头
l have no fucking idea what to... ...write.
新买的?
ls that new?
升到2.0版本了
That's the 2.0 upgraded version.
我是"通行无阻"的罗比
l'm totally mobile now. Nice.
还有美味可口的…
This is Hall Pass with Robbie Mercer...
"我有大奶也有大脑"奥莉薇雅
...here with the luscious Olivia "Don't look at my tits, l have a mind" Morris.
伍兹伯勒凶杀案纪念日的题目是…
Here is my Woodsboro Massacre anniversary question...
你最喜欢的恐怖片是哪部?
what is your favorite scary movie?
你就这么点智商?
ls that all you've got?
只会问这种白痴问题?
Some stupid douche question?
对啊,你从哪学来的?
Yeah, where'd you hear that anyways?
是"刺杀1"的对话
lt's a line from Stab 1 , duh.
嗨,查理
Hey, Charlie.
你也很爱恐怖片,可碧
You're a genre nut, Kirby.
你最喜欢的恐怖片是哪部?
What's your favorite scary movie?
小鹿班比
Bambi.
你好幽默,可碧
Dork. What? That's funny, Kirby.
她根本无视于你
Completely unaware you exist.
才怪,她哈死我了
No, man, she wants me.
你认为不可能吗?混蛋
Yeah, l wish, right? Asshole.
我觉得查理喜欢你
l think Charlie likes you.
我也喜欢他
And l like him.
我想逗他、折磨他、让他吃鳖
To tease, to torment, to make him squirm.
你可以整死他,相信我
You could do a lot worse, trust me.
嗨,崔佛
Oh, hi, Trevor.
掰,崔佛
Bye, Trevor.
能谈一下吗?
Can we talk?
有人很在乎你,知道吗?
Somebody cares about you over here, you know?
那个曾让你快乐过的人
Someone who made you really happy once.
那个永远不该抛弃你的人
Someone who never should have let you go.
当你挂电话时
When you're done with a phone call,
就该让人家走
you let someone go.
当你送人去机场时
Or when you take someone to the airport,
就该让人家走
you let them go.
当你对人家说你爱她
When you tell someone you love her,
她就给了你全部
she gives you everything
然后你就马上去追别人
and then you just go out with someone else,
那可不是让人家走
that is not letting her go.
那叫甩掉人家,懂吗?
That's dumping her. Okay?
那叫做背叛
That's ... that's betrayal.
崔佛塞顿被打枪了
Trevor Sheldon, denied,
罗比在"通行无阻"为您直播
live on Hall Pass with Robbie Mercer.
你最喜欢的恐怖片是哪部?
What is your favorite scary movie, man?
让我告诉你…
l'll show you.
我渐渐相信自己只能做个受害者
And l began to believe myself that that was all l was... a victim...
这是我无法接受的
...and that was unacceptable to me.
所以…
So...
我坐下来…
...l sat down...
开始写作
...and began to write a new role
为自己创造新的角色
that would be my own.
一个克服恐惧的女性角色
A role for a woman who could leave the walls of fear behind...
并且重返阳光之下
...and step back into the sunlight.
走出黑暗,重返光明
...out of darkness.
谢谢你
Thank you.
好吧
Okay,
签书会马上就要开始了
we're gonna start the book signing in a sec...
所以请踊跃抢购
...so buy your copies while they last.
我说的就是各位
l'm looking at you, ladies.
盖儿,很高兴你能来
Gale. l'm glad you came.
恭喜你,席妮
Congratulations, Sidney.
我还没读过你的书
l haven't had a chance to read it yet, but....
我知道哪里有卖
l know where you can get one.
杜威!
Dewey! Hey!
嗨,席妮
Hey, Sid.
盖儿,你也来了
Gale, you made it.
你不是要工作吗?
What's going on, Dewey?
席妮,真抱歉
Sid, l'm sorry,
我是来办事的
l gotta do something here.
真的很抱歉
l'm really sorry.
打扰一下!
Excuse me!
很快就好了
This will only take a minute.
请各位安静地留在原地
l need you all to stay where you are and remain silent.
全部不准离开,谢谢各位
Nobody leaves yet. The Sheriff thanks you.
不能等会儿吗,臭条子?
Can this wait, Barney Fife?
我正在办活动
l'm running an event here.
女士,现在是警察在办案
Ma'am, this is a police event now.
到底怎么回事?
What's going on?
盖儿,警察在办案
Gale, this is police business.
麻烦你让我们工作
lf you could just let us handle this.
我在跟我老公说话,茱蒂警员
l'm talking to my husband, Deputy Judy.
听着
Listen, there's a phone we believe may have been taken
案发现场的手机可能在这
from the scene of a crime.
希克斯警员发现讯号来自这里
Deputy Hicks has traced its location back to these coordinates.
其他的不能透露
The rest is needtoknow.
我又不是一般人
l'm not " needtoknow" ?
警长,铃声来自这里!
Sheriff, it's ringing out here!
在这里!
There!
从后车厢发出来的!
lt's coming from the trunk!
杜威?
Dewey?
请大家往后退!
Gonna need everyone to stay back!
- 我现在没空 - 车是我租的
Not now, Sid. lt's my rental.
好了,这里变成案发现场了
Okay, it's now an official crime scene.
封锁现场
Let's lock it down.
不准拍照!
Get that camera out of here!
大家退后
Everybody back.
这最好只是恶作剧
Please tell me this is a prank, Dewey.
恐怕不是
l'm afraid not, Sid.
走吧
Come on.
Henry, you're not gonna believe what just happened.
退后,盖儿
Stand back, Gale.
我只是想看一下
l just wanna see.
星期二记得交作文
Okay, essays are due Tuesday.
题目是"伍兹伯勒是好所在…"
"Why Woodsboro is the best"
手机请全部关掉,这是校规!
Anything with an on/off switch should be off, that's the rule!
有人要分享故事吗?
Somebody wanna share?
珍妮兰道和玛妮库柏昨晚被杀了
Jenny Randall and Marnie Cooper were murdered last night.
什么?
What?
被刺死的
Stabbed to death.
- 你最喜欢的恐怖片… - 闭嘴啦
What's your favorite scary Shut up!
- 天啊 - 怎么了?
Yo, it's a news van!
还没下课!
Class is not over!
媒体已经来了
That was fast.
本周正逢知名的…
This week marks the anniversary
伍兹伯勒凶杀案周年纪念日
of the infamous Woodsboro Murders.
两名少女被杀的那天
Two girls killed the exact day...
当地知名的幸存者席妮皮斯考克
local celebrity victim Sidney Prescott
选择于此时回到她的家乡
chose to return to her hometown.
案子可能是盖儿小说中的剧情
lt all could be something right out of a Gale Weathers bestseller.
她目前在哪里呢?
And where is she now?
就住在伍兹伯勒
Well, living right here in Woodsboro.
瑞利太太
Mrs. Riley. -Hoss.
- 第一夫人 - 柏金斯
First Lady. Perkins.
抱歉,盖儿,他正在问话
Excuse me, Gale. He's conducting an interview.
太好了,我最爱访问了
Great. l love interviews.
你得等一会儿
You'll have to wait, Gale. Sorry.
抱歉,不能让你过去
Can't let you in there.
不然怎样,抓我吗,茱蒂警员?
What are you gonna do, arrest me, Deputy Judy?
如果市民干扰警察办案
lf it comes to it. Civilian interfrerence with a police investigation...
法院是可以判罪的
poses many a problem in a court of law.
好,你给我听着
Okay, listen to me, Judy.
我不介意你跟我老公一起工作
l don't mind that you're working with my husband...
想做蛋糕给他吃也没关系
...or that you even bake him those little treats as you do.
但如果你想学他讲话
But if you're gonna start acting like him...
那就先留点胡子
you gotta put a moustache on
你的声音根本不像
because you sound ridiculous.
- 盖儿! - 茱蒂!
Gale. Judy!
盖儿!
Gale.
警员、盖儿
别这样
Please.
席妮,麻烦稍等一下
Uh, Sidney, if you don't mind giving us a minute....
- 席妮 - 嗨,盖儿
Sid. Hi, Gale.
杜威
Dewey,
麻烦跟上头讲一下
would you please explain to Betty Crocker...
我有权利来这里
...that l have every right to be here?
如果又发生凶杀案…很明显的…
lf there's been another murder in Woodsboro, obviously...
什么?
What?
这些资讯不能公开!
That is not public information!
网路早就已经传遍了
lt is all over the lnternet, Dewey!
- 真的吗? - 当然!
lt is? -Yes!
全世界都比我先知道!
The whole world knows about it before me!
她想参与调查,警长
She wants to be a part of the investigation, Sheriff.
等一下
Hang on.
不知道你有没有听说过…
are you familiar with the phrase,
那本书是我写的?
"l wrote the book on this" ?
我不想惹你生气
Gale, with all due respect...
但我不觉得两者有关联…
l don't see how that pertains to...
我的书就在讲这个!
Because l wrote the book on this!
"伍兹伯勒凶杀案"…
The Woodsboro Murders
作者盖儿魏瑟丝?
by Gale Weathers?
但你不再是记者了,盖儿
But you're not a reporter anymore, Gale.
就算你是…
And even if you were...
别把我当做媒体
Don't treat me like l'm the media.
我协助警方破案
l helped solve these things...
三次了,记得吗?
...three times, remember?
我们一起合作的
You and me. Together.
但我已经是警长了
But l'm the Sheriff now, Gale.
是吗?
Right?
怎么?你不让我帮你了?
What? You're not gonna let me help you with this?
我没办法
l can't .
好,那我就自己搞定
All right, then l'm going rogue.
这是我最擅长的
This is what l'm good at, Dewey.
用我自己的方式
This is what l know how to do.
你的蛋糕吃起来像屎
Your lemon squares taste like ass.
- 不像,真的不像 - 谢谢长官
They don't . They really don't . Thank you, sir.
- 警长 - 怎么了?
Sheriff. -Yeah?
局里来了几个高中生
We've got a couple high school kids in here.
有两个说早上接到恐吓电话
Two of 'em, they say they got threatening phone calls this morning
是由受害者的手机拨的
from the victims‘ phones.
奥莉薇雅莫里斯和吉儿罗伯兹
Names are Olivia Morris and Jill Roberts.
那是席妮的表妹
That's Sid's cousin.
真棘手
Damn.
Right in here, Sheriff.
- 嗨,吉儿 - 席妮
Hey, Jill. Sidney.
嗨
Hi. Hi.
很高兴见到你,虽然场合不太对
lt's nice to see you, even under the circumstances.
- 你还好吧? - 没事
You okay? Yeah.
接到电话的就是你们?
So two of you got phone calls?
就是我们
Yeah, us two.
你最喜欢的恐怖片是哪部?
"What's your favorite scary movie?"
是杀手的声音
lt was the killer's voice.
跟"刺杀"的一样
From Stab.
你应该最清楚
Or, l mean, you know, from your life.
我叫可碧
l'm Kirby, by the way.
是她们的朋友
l'm their friend.
- 杀手没打给你吗? - 没有
And the killer didn't call you? No.
这是坏事吗?
ls that a bad thing?
这表示我会比她们先死吗?
Does that mean that l'm not gonna live as long as these two?
是啊…或许吧
No. Maybe.
当然不会
Of course not. Just...
小…心点就是了
...just be careful.
天啊,听到了没?
Oh, my God, did you hear that?
下一个就是我!
l'm gonna be next!
我不该回来的,我应该马上离开
Dewey, l shouldn't be here. l should leave town.
你恐怕还不能走,席妮
l'm afraid that's not really possible, Sidney.
听着,没有人怀疑你
Look, nobody thinks you're involved...
但每个人都有嫌疑,抱歉
but everyone's a suspect. l'm sorry.
车上的证据表示凶手跟你有关联
And there was evidence in your car, connecting the killer to you.
你可能是重要证人
You may be a material witness.
所以警方会全天候保护你
So, you'll have 24hour police surveillance.
真让人宽心
That's comforting.
我是蕾贝卡
This is Rebecca.
我的老天爷,亨利!
Oh, my fucking God, Henry!
全都是真的
Yes, it's true.
有两个女孩被杀了
Two girls butchered.
发财了
Payday.
我很不喜欢这个地方
l was so not feeling Woodsboro.
原以为只是个烂活动
l was like lame PR move, right?
现在爽爆了
Well, fuck me wow.
这点子太棒了
Best idea ever.
亨利,等会打给你
Henry, l'll call you back.
抱歉,我要起肖一下
Excuse me, l have to geek out.
之前没机会跟你说
l didn't get a chance to say something earlier,
- 但很荣幸见到你 - 谢谢
but it's such an honor to meet you. Thank you.
- 蕾贝卡华特斯 - 你好
Rebecca Walters. -Hi.
我小时候最爱看的…
When l was a kid, it was all about...
就是盖儿魏瑟丝的"火线追踪"
Top Story with Gale Weathers.
你是我当时的偶像
You were my '90s.
现在是盖儿瑞利了
Well, it's Gale Riley now.
你为爱牺牲,我知道
You gave it all up for love, l know that.
- 你们结婚多久了? - 十年了
How long have you and Dewey been married? Ten years.
跟"刺杀3"的剧情一样
Just like your characters in Stab 3. Wow.
Wow.
不是不好的意思
l didn't mean bad wow.
感觉这只是电影中的情节
lt just always seemed like more of a movie romance than a real one
在现实生活中,你们不可能…
because it was a movie and in real life you two would never be....
真尴尬
Ooh, dug a hole.
重来一次,这样说吧
Climbing out here. So anyway...
我很佩服你的勇气
kudos on being brave enough
为爱放弃大好事业
to drop off the professional map.
有计划重建你的烂名声吗?
Any plans on revitalizing your tarnished brand?
听好,再过两秒
Listen, in about two seconds,
我就会用"烂名声"
l'm gonna " revitalize" your face...
"重建"你的脸
...with my "tarnished brand" !
我还是很呛嘛
l still got it.
Testy.
她好漂亮
She's so pretty.
我以为生还者会全身都是疤
When you think about what she's survived she must have scars everywhere.
她妈妈是我妹妹
Her mom was my sister.
我也受伤过
l have scars, too.
可是都没人关心我
No one ever asks me about my scars.
抱歉,罗伯兹太太
l'm sorry, Mrs. Roberts.
她说的是刀疤,妈
She means knife scars, Mom.
那…好吧
Well, fine.
你还好吗?盖儿还好吧?
How are you? How's Gale?
我还好
l'm all right.
可是盖儿…她不好受
But Gale... ...it's been hard on her.
住在小镇上,嫁给了乡下人
Small town... ...small town husband.
没有题材可以写
Not much to write about.
你们俩的关系还好吧?
You two okay?
我读过一篇文章…
Well, l read somewhere once...
"当你认为倒楣透顶时…"
"Just when you think things can't get any worse...
"有时并非如此"
sometimes they don't .
"有时事情反而会好转"
Sometimes they get better."
"重返光明"第220页
Out of Darkness by Sidney Prescott, page 220.
我得先走了
l've gotta get going.
很高兴见到你,杜威
lt's nice to see you, Dewey.
我们一起经历过大风大浪
We've been through a lot together.
这次也不会有事的
And we'll get through this, too. Okay?
把门锁好
Lock up.
别怕…是我
Be cool. lt's okay. Relax, relax. lt's just me.
你来干嘛?外面全是警察!
What the hell are you doing here? There are cops right out front!
条子搞不定忍者的,宝贝
No match for the ninja, baby.
席妮到底在你家做什么?
Anyway, what are you doing in the house with Sidney Prescott?
你这样会引来杀身之祸的
l mean, that's like being on Top Chef with Jeffrey Dahmer.
你能不能离窗户远一点?
Can you please get away from the window?
你不准来这里,别再来了
You have no right to be in here. Not anymore.
等一下
Hang on.
听说杀手有打给你
l heard you got a phone call from the killer.
是真的吗?
ls that true?
关你什么事?
What do you care?
你不觉得我在身边比较安全吗?
Don't you think you'd be a lot safer with me around?
我不相信你,崔佛
l don't trust you, Trevor. Hey.
那我就想办法让你相信我
Then l'm just gonna have to make sure that you do.
好吗?
All right?
抱歉,我不知道…
Oh, sorry. l didn't ....
没关系,他要走了…
No, he's just leaving.
我的前男友
lt's my ex.
没错,她的挚爱
Yeah. Her one and only.
- 嗨 - 嗨
Hi. Hi.
能见到本人真屌
lt's cool to meet you...officially.
我一直想买你的书,只是…
l keep meaning to pick up a copy of your book, but....
你本人比较娇小
You're smaller in person.
怎么了?
What?
没事,只是你让我想起…
Nothing. Just, you remind me of...
我自己
me.
把窗户锁好,好吗?
Lock your window, okay?
- 好,晚安 - 晚安
Yeah. Good night. 'Night.
不好意思
Sorry about that.
只是离开前再巡一次
Just making my rounds before taking off.
好,谢谢
Great. Thanks.
你不记得我了,对吧?
You don't remember me, do you?
什么?
Sorry?
我们是高中同学
We went to high school together.
茱蒂希克丝
Judy Hicks.
我们去同一间指导室
We had the same homeroom.
还有戏剧社
And Drama Club, too.
我们还一起演过小飞侠
We were in Peter Pan together.
我演迷路的男孩
l played a Lost Boy.
你演…老虎莉莉
You were... Tiger Lily.
抱歉,我不记得了
l'm sorry, that was a long time ago.
没关系
lt's okay.
你之前的故事还不少
You had a lot of stuff going on back then.
很高兴再见到你,茱蒂
Well, it's nice to see you again, Judy.
我也是
You too.
楼上还好吗?
Everything okay upstairs?
你应该去前面的
You're supposed to be out front, Perkins.
勇气的另一种说法是?
What's a fourletter word for courage?
带种
"Guts."
那是奥莉薇雅莫里斯,住隔壁
That's Olivia Morris. She lives next door.
她在名单上
She's on the list.
她可以住我隔壁没关系
She can live next door to me.
给我听好,玛莉…
Now seriously, uh, uh, Mary,
我警告你,听到没?
l'm , l'm warning you, okay?
我真的会动手,我不骗你
l'm gonna have to get physical. l mean it.
我受够了!别碰我!
This is it! l'm .... Fuck off!
"奥莉薇亚"
- 喂? - 你们在干嘛?
Hello? What are you guys up to?
在看"活人甡吃"
We're watching Shaun of the Dead.
你知道外面车上有两个僵尸吗?
You know there are two zombies sitting outside your house in a car?
知道,是条子
Yup. They're cops.
你要来吗?
You wanna come up?
死亡天使走了吗?
Did the Angel of Death leave?
没有,她在客房里
No, she's in the guest room.
算了,我待在隔壁就好了
Forget it. Next door's close enough.
你妈在家吗?
Your mom home?
她去男友家了
She's at her boyfriend's .
这里晚上好可怕
lt's creepy around here tonight.
僵尸还在车上
Well, the zombies are still in their car...
所以你会很安全的
...so you should be all right.
- 明天连络,好吗? - 好的
Call me tomorrow, okay? All right.
- 她不想过来? - 她怕死神
She didn't wanna come up? She fears the Reaper.
看我的
Watch this.
请讲
Speaking.
你最喜欢的恐怖片是哪部?
What's your favorite scary movie, Olivia?
这是我听过最不像的,吉儿
That's the worst imitation l've ever heard, Jill.
讲到这个,"刺拉松"办在哪?
Speaking of " Stab," have you heard where the StabaThon is gonna be yet?
没听说,反正与我无关
No, and it doesn't matter to me anyways.
我妈又不让我去
My mom doesn't let me go.
是崔佛,让我来听
lt's Trevor. l'll handle this.
崔佛又打来了
Trevor's calling. Again.
- 你想干嘛? - 我要找吉儿
What do you want? l wanna talk to Jill.
不行,我是可碧
No, it's Kirby.
抱歉,崔佛
Sorry, Trevor.
吉儿不接任何前男友的电话
Jill is screening her calls from all past relationships.
你们在搞什么?
What's going on over there?
等一下,他在讲什么?
Hang on a sec. What is he saying?
- 我不是崔佛 - 什么?
l'm not Trevor. What?
我听不清楚,崔佛
l can barely hear you, Trevor.
- 我不是崔佛 - 好吧
This isn't Trevor.
那你为何有他的手机?
Oh, all right. Well then, why do you have his phone... whoever this is?
他想假扮鬼面杀手
He's trying to do Ghostface.
这家伙怪怪的
He's being weird.
我找吉儿讲话
l want to talk to Jill.
既然她不想跟你说话
Okay, well, she doesn't wanna talk to you.
来吧,鬼面先生,悄悄跟我说吧
Come on, Mr. Ghostface, whisper to me.
不是应该问我问题吗?
Aren't you supposed to ask me a question?
好吧
All right.
- 电影好看吗? - 什么电影?
How's the movie? What movie?
- "活人甡吃" - 你怎么知道的?
Shaun of the Dead. How did you know that?
因为我在衣柜里
Because l'm standing in the closet.
少来了,你才没有
Stop. You are not.
怎么回事?
What's going on?
如果是崔佛的话,还蛮怪的
Trevor's being weird. l mean, if it is him. l don't know.
- 我不太确定 - 什么?
What?
我他妈的不是崔佛!
This is not fucking Trevor!
那你他妈的是谁?
Well then, who the fuck are you?
把衣柜打开
Open the closet door.
你知道外面都是警察吧?
You do know there are cops all over this house?
杀你们不需要很久
l think l'd have just enough time to slice someone open.
- 我…我来跟他说 - 别吵
l'll talk to him.
你们在搞什么鬼?
What's going on over there, you guys?
抱歉,我不知道
Sorry. l don't know.
- 可碧 - 安静
Kirby. Kirby.
来,开门吧
Come on, do it.
- 你不可能在里面的 - 自己看吧
There is no way you're in there. See for yourself.
可碧,别这样
Kirby, come on. Talk to me.
告诉我,这并不好笑
This isn't funny. Kirby.
骗子,我不跟你玩了
Liar. l'm over this.
我没有说是你的衣柜
l never said l was in your closet.
什么?
What?
奥莉薇雅!
Olivia!
天啊!
Oh, God!
不要!
Stop!
豪斯!
Hoss!
柏金斯!
Perkins!
惨了!
Shit!
你想干嘛?
What?
欢迎回来,席妮
Welcome home, Sidney.
刚才只是电影预告
Preview of coming events.
为何不直接找我?
Why don't you come for me?
你有那个胆吗?
You got the balls for that?
可怜的席妮
Oh, poor Sidney.
竟然还把自己当成是主角
You think this is all about you. You think you're still the star.
- 这不是在拍电影! - 将会是的
This isn't a fucking movie! lt will be.
- 他们是无辜的 - 别再说教了
These are innocent people. Spare me the lecture.
你的成就还不是靠这些死人?
You've done very well by all this bloodshed, haven't you?
那离开家乡又怎么说?
Well, how about the town you left behind?
我帮你计划好了
l've got plans for you.
我帮你割掉眼皮
l'm gonna slit your eyelids in half
杀你时,你就不必眨眼了
so you don't blink when l stab you in the face.
我随时都可以要你的命
You'll die when l want you to, Sidney.
在杀你之前
Not a moment before.
我会慢慢地折磨你
Until then...you're going to suffer.
席妮!
Sidney!
吉儿,不要进来!
Jill! Stay right there!
- 她是不是… - 不要看
ls she... Do not look. Okay?
她说你是死亡天使
She said you were the Angel of Death.
小心!
- 他在这里 - 他在哪里?
He's in here. Where is he?
刚才还在这
He was.
- 吉儿? - 别过来
Don't! Jill?
怎么回事?
What happened?
天啊,吉儿!
Oh, my God, Jill!
老天啊!
Jesus!
是我,我在这,走吧
Hey, it's me, l'm here. Let's go.
我们去医院,好吗?
Let's go. That's it. All right?
吉儿!
Jill!
天啊,你没事吧?
Oh, my God. Are you okay?
拿去,压住止血
Here, keep pressure on it.
后院没有人
There's nobody back there.
Call it in. Right.
Hey.
你没事吧?
Are you okay?
上楼检查一下
You should look upstairs.
我以为早就结束了!
l thought this was over!
都是你的错,席妮
lt's all your fault, Sidney.
你跟你妈一样!
You're just like your mother!
我收回之前的话
l'm sorry about what l said.
要不要去检查一下?
Do you wanna get that looked at?
也好
Yeah.
到底发生什么事?
What the hell happened?
他跑到第二间屋子的后院里
l saw him go into that yard two houses down right before.
然后我就绕过去拦截他
Yeah, and l circled around to cut him off.
然后呢?
And?
我见到豪斯从另一边出来
And l met Hoss coming from the other direction.
他八成绕道逃掉了,像鬼魂一样
Yeah, l know, he must've circled back around somehow. He's like a ghost.
- 老大,很抱歉 - 我们很自责
Chief, we're sorry. We feel terrible.
算了,先回去吧
All right. Get outta here.
伍兹伯勒高中的同学们
This is Hall Pass with Robbie Mercer...
我是"通行无阻"的罗比…
webcasting live in
在黑暗时刻为您网路直播
our darkest hour.
纪念日发生了连续杀人事件
What began as a day of remembrance has ended with serial murder.
死都不跟我约会的奥莉薇雅
Olivia Morris, who officially will never go out with me...
现在真的死了
...is dead.
还有珍妮兰道和玛妮库柏
So is Jenny Randall and Marnie Cooper.
本地的传奇,"刺杀"系列
Our local legacy, the Stab movies,
已成为真实案件
is coming to life.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
你是用那玩意儿拍的?
Are you recording with that thing?
直接上传部落格
Live videoblog upload.
他在做网路直播
He's webcasting right now.
可以关一下吗?
Mind turning it off?
来个老掉牙的"不留纪录"?
For a little oldschool " off the record" ?
不能不顾观众权益
Can't . Owe it to my audience.
- 给我他妈的关掉 - 好吧
Turn that fucking thing off. Okay.
电影社就是两位负责的吗?
So, you two are the boys that run the movie club at Woodsboro High?
查理是老板,我是副总
Charlie runs it. l'm just V.P.
- 他挂了就换我当老板 - 是影业社
ln case he takes a bullet. lt's called Cinema Club.
学校里的电影粉丝你们一定很熟
So you must have a very unique insight into the movie buffs at your school.
或许吧
Maybe.
我们一起合作抓凶手如何?
What if we could catch the killer by working together?
两个世代的菁英份子
Two generations of cuttingedge journalists...
共同为媒体付出热情
intertwining our passions for media?
两位意下如何?
What would you say?
- 爱死你了 - 好极了
l love you. Very good.
用你们的专业
Now you give me your expertise on
找出热爱恐怖片的同学名单
the gore geek scene at Woodsboro High...
我就给你们点好处
and maybe l give you something in return.
例如请明星来参观影业社?
Say a celebrity visit to your Cinema Club?
我来找
By me.
席妮可以吗?
What about Sidney?
席妮怎么了?
What about Sidney? Yeah, you know her, right?
你认识她吧?你们不是朋友吗?
l mean, you're friends with her.
恕我直言,她能来就太屌了
No offense, but that'd be a big deal for Cinema Club.
席妮皮斯考克来参观?
A visit from Sidney Prescott?
她是个大明星
l mean, she's the star.
当然
Yes,
她是哈利波特,我就是罗琳
she's Daniel Radcliffe to my J.K. Rowling.
只是你的书不畅销,票房也很烂
Without the book sales and the box office.
管他的
Whatever.
骨头没有断,没什么大碍
There's no broken bones. l think you'll be fine.
好好休养,你算幸运了
Just take a couple weeks off.
所以…席妮
So, Sidney, ooh, ow.
我就长话短说吧
Anyway, long story short...
公司要马上签三本书的合约
Random wants to lock you in to three more books now.
有看到合约的空白处吗?
See the blank line in your contract?
金额随便你填
You can name your price.
等警察一调查完
And as soon as you're clear in this investigation...
我们就搭下一班飞机去纽约
we're on the next plane to New York.
我已经约了晨间新闻、观点
l booked Today, The View,
南茜葛瑞斯和MTV新闻
Nancy Grace, MTV News
抱歉,可以问个问题吗?
Excuse me. Can l ask you a question?
你读过我的书吗?
Did you read my book?
我想等电影出来
Thought l'd wait for the movie.
- 新书发表会结束了 - 席妮
Book tour's over. Sidney.
接受事实吧
Accept your situation.
你这辈子都是受害者
You're a victim. For life.
所以接受它,利用它
So embrace it, use it.
我知道你在乎你的读者
l know you care about your readers.
那些被践踏过的倒楣鬼
All those little downtrodden fucks...
他们只想寻求依靠
that just need a light at the end of their tunnel
免得全部都去跳河
so they don't jump off a bridge.
这种机会怎能放弃?
And a lucky break like this?
我讲的是至少一倍的销售量
l'm talking 100% increase in sales, minimum.
等于多一百万人知道你的理念
That's maybe a million more people get your message...
而你又能多赚点钱
and you get a ton more checks.
双赢
Winwin.
- 我不再需要你了 - 席妮
l won't be needing you anymore. Sidney.
- 你被开除了 - 开除了?
You're fired.
- 开除了 - 很好
Fired? Fired. Fine.
你读过我的书吗,蕾贝卡?
"Have you even read my book, Rebecca?"
你读过吗?
"Have you"
席妮的毛病就是缺男人
The problem with Sidney is that she never gets laid.
起码偶尔也该醉一下
Or even a little shitfaced once in a while.
晚上就会打来道歉了
She'll call me tonight and apologize.
看着吧
Just watch.
她会想通的
She'll come around.
给她点时间
Gotta just give her time and
席妮就会想通了
Sidney will come around.
车子呢?
Where did l....?
我是蕾贝卡
This is Rebecca.
请找席妮皮斯考克
Sidney Prescott, please.
我是皮斯考克小姐的公关
l'm handling Miss Prescott's calls and appearances.
- 请问要留讯息吗? - 你就是讯息
May l take a message? You are the message.
- 你有在写吗? - 我在写
Are you writing this down? Yes, l am.
你的声音不是很清楚
lt's kind of hard to hear you.
我跟席妮正在医院
l'm in the hospital with Sidney.
麻烦你稍等一下
lf you could just hang on one second.
我有的是时间
l've got time.
赶时间的是你
lt's you that doesn't .
蕾贝卡,你听起来不像在医院
You know, Rebecca, it doesn't sound to me like you're in the hospital.
倒像是在停车场里
Sounds like you're in a parking garage.
一座黑暗废弃的停车场
A dark and deserted parking garage.
但如果你想去医院
But if you want to be in the hospital,
我很乐意送你一程…
l'd be happy to put you there.
到停尸间!
ln the morgue!
讨厌!
No!
救命!
Help!
Help! Help me! Help!
夹着尾巴逃吧,混蛋!
Cut and run, you fucking bastard!
警方正在积极调查中
This is an ongoing investigation.
请别担心
Rest assured...
我们锁定了几个目标
we're pursuing a number of leads.
我透露的越少越好
The less l say about that, the better.
你们可以发问了
So l'm taking questions.
- 警长… - 杜威!
Dewey! Sheriff...
盖儿?
Gale?
这些凶杀案是否在模仿…
Any comment on the fact that these killings seem to resemble...
原版的伍兹伯勒凶杀案?
the pattern of the original Woodsboro Murders?
老婆?晚点再说
Hon? Later.
正如我所说…
As l was saying...
警方目前都在努力调查
my officers are hard at work,
我们希望大家知道…
and we just want the community to know
警方已经快掌控情势了
that we are very close to bringing this whole situation under control
哇!
快上大楼的屋顶!快去!
Get up to the top of the structure! Go, go!
大家后退!往后退!
Everyone back! Stay back!
全部都不准动!
Listen,
派人去每个楼梯守着
l want a man on each stairwell.
掌控情势是吗,警长?
lt's all under control, huh, Sheriff?
不然还能说什么?
What am l supposed to say?
听好,虽然我不是警察
Listen, l may not be wearing a uniform...
但是我有你们没有的线索
but l happen to have a lead and you don't .
想加入盖儿团队再来找我
So let me know when you're back on Team Gale.
快去,菜鸟们!
Move it, amateurs!
影业社的会员们
Okay, Cinema Club.
现在聚会开始,欢迎各位
We are now in session. Welcome.
先向各位做个简介
Tell you a little bit about ourselves.
敝社是学校认可的校外活动
We are a sanctioned afterschool activity...
比歌咏团低一级
one rung below the Glee Club,
比Wii Fit团高两级
two above Nintendo Wii Fit.
先让我欢迎我们的贵宾
And let me just say to our guest,
席妮皮斯考克
Sidney Prescott...
这是无比的荣幸
it's an honor.
超越洁美李寇蒂斯
Beyond Jamie Lee Curtis,
打败琳达布莱儿
forget Linda Blair...
她才是最屌的
l mean, this is the ultimate.
谢谢,不敢当
Thanks. l guess.
这个…你把高中生活拍下来
This? You film your entire high school experience...
然后放在网路上播?
and what, post it on the net?
以后所有人都会这样做的
Everybody'll be doing it someday, Sid.
杀手少的就是这个东西
lt's kind of the one component the killer's missing.
什么意思?
What do you mean?
如果真的想要创新
Well, if you wanna be the newnew version.
杀手就应该拍下杀人过程
The killer should be filming the murders.
这才是变态杀手的突破
Yeah, it's like the natural next step
全程实况拍摄
in a psycho slasher innovation.
在警察来抓人之前…
l mean, you film them all real time,
把影片全部上传
and then before you get caught... you upload them into cyberspace.
这一切将永远流传
Making your art as immortal as you.
- 但我不是说他 - 但可不是我
Not to implicate him. Not to implicate me.
你们认为凶手是谁?
So who do you think is behind the murders?
绝对是"刺杀"的热爱者
Well, it's a Stab fanatic clearly.
不想拍续集,只想翻拍原作
Working on less of a shriekquel and more of a screammake.
版权上的用语
Copyrighted terms, by the way.
现在几乎都是翻拍的
'Cause all there are now are remakes.
只有恐怖片是允许的
Only horror the studios greenlight.
不过仍然有规则
l mean, there are still rules...
但规则改了
but the rules have changed.
意想不到的结局是新惯例
The unexpected is the new cliche.
对,开头一定要够刺激
Yeah, you gotta have an opening sequence that blows the doors off...
加上很屌的音乐和画面
dial up some flashy musicvideo direction...
杀人方式一定要更残酷
and the kills gotta be way more extreme.
现在的观众很了以前的手法
Modern audiences get savvy to the rules of the originals...
所以逆向操作成为新指标
so the reversals become the new standard.
在现代恐怖片中怎样才能存活?
ln fact, the only surefire way to survive a modern horror movie?
你基本上要够gay
You pretty much have to be gay.
你们怎能肯定…
So why are you so sure
凶手的手法跟翻拍一样?
that the killer's working by the rules of a horror remake?
原版的"刺杀"故事很单纯
The original Stab structure is pretty apparent.
对,父母不在家
Yeah, two kids killed in a house
两个孩子就被杀了
when their parents are away...
接着是学校里的辣妹
and then the school's hot
不知不觉就被嗝屁了
chick savaged beyond recognition.
接下来的大家都知道
We all know where it goes from there.
- 派对 - 没错,就是派对
A party. Exactly. A party.
第三段绝对是大屠杀
Guaranteed third act main cast bloodbath.
希望能多露点奶子
Fingers crossed on some nudity for a change.
你知道今晚哪里有派对吗?
Okay, so do you know of a party that's happening tonight?
有一场刺拉松
Well, there's StabaThon.
刺拉松?
StabaThon?
就是电影马拉松
lt's a movie marathon.
一次看完七集"刺杀"
All seven Stabs backtoback.
我们每年都会办
We do it every year.
就在今晚?
And it's tonight?
有杀手正在仿效电影行凶手法杀人
There's a killer out there patterning his murders after the original movie.
我知道,超疯狂的
l know. lt's pretty wild.
你必须取消它
Well, you have to call it off.
这个…今天是星期五
Okay, l mean, it's Friday.
伍兹伯勒有很多人办派对
l'm sure we're not the only party that's going on in Woodsboro.
你说的那个刺拉松派对办在哪?
So where is this circle jerk gonna take place?
有谁想玩电影问答?
So who's ready for this Q & A?
别这样…我真的想知道地点
No, no. l really want the location.
那是个秘密活动
You know, it's kind of an underground thing.
只靠电邮连络,非常私密
Email invites, pretty secret.
你真的不打算说?真的吗?
What, you're not gonna tell me? Really?
我们是队友,记得吗?
We're working together. Remember?
- 所以你要玩电影问答? - 去你的
So are you ready for that Q & A? Fuck you. Let's go.
真够屌的
That was awesome.
感觉就像是居家监禁
l feel like l'm under house arrest.
当人家说"我知道你的感受"时
You know when people say, "l know how you feel" ...
其实通常只是说说而已
but you know they're just saying that because they really have...
因为他们根本不懂你的感受
no frigging idea how you feel?
但我知道你的感受
l know how you feel.
奥莉薇雅的事我很遗憾
l'm so sorry about Olivia.
你公关的事我也很遗憾
l'm sorry about your publicist.
你是如何处理的?
How do you handle it?
大家老是盯着你看?
People staring at you all the time?
大家都盯着我吗?
People stare at me?
我就无法面对人们的目光
l could never handle that kind of attention.
我只会…
l just...
感到人生就这样完蛋了
...feel like it would take over your whole life.
我的作法是…
What l do is l...
试着别去想自己
...try not to think about me.
我有很在乎的人…
l have people l care about...
所以把焦点放他们身上
...and l focus on them.
其他的就迎刃而解了
And the rest, it works out.
你昨晚救了我一命
You saved my life last night.
我知道我们是一家人
l mean, l know we're family,
但你和我根本不熟
but you hardly know me.
所以我不知道…
lt makes me wonder, you know, if...
自己有没有胆量做一样的事
...l'd have been brave enough to do the same thing.
我希望你永远都不用知道
l really hope you never have to find that out.
那么…
Well...
需要我的话
...if you need me,
你知道我在哪里
you know where to find me.
我会在牢房…我是说我的房间里
l'll be up in my cell. Or, l mean, my room.
她的房间都封起来了
Her room's all boarded up.
这就是牢房的装潢
That's the view from my cell.
感觉好奇怪
lt's really weird.
奥莉薇雅会体谅的
l think Olivia would understand, okay?
她希望我多交些朋友
She'd want me to be around other people.
我的妈啊
Holy shit.
我好像来到驴蛋星球了
Even if l did just crashland on Planet Dork.
说到驴蛋,崔佛就来了
Speaking of which, Trevor's here.
嗨,可碧
Hey, Kirby. What is he doing there?
他去干嘛?那又不是他会去的场合
That is so not his scene.
我也不懂
l have no idea.
他可能以为你会来吧
Maybe he thought you would be here.
会来才怪
Yeah, fat chance.
经过昨晚的事哪有可能?
After what happened last night?
我妈都快吓死了
l mean, my mom is just completely freaked out. it's not pretty.
好吧,你就当个乖乖女
All right, look. You go do your " good girl" thing
我就帮你多喝点吧
and l will drink for the both of us.
随时更新状态
l will keep you posted.
好吧,小心点
All right. Be safe.
刺拉松…
Stabathon! Stabathon!
谢谢…
Thank you! Thank you!
谢谢…(西语)
Gracias, gracias.
影业社感谢各位
Cinema Club thanks you for coming out
参加第三届刺拉松!
for our third annual Stabathon!
人多势众,朋友们!
Safety in numbers, my friends!
人多势众!
Safety in numbers!
大家都得喝…
Who's ready to drink every time someone
只要有人手机没讯号
can't get a cell phone signal?
大家都得喝…
Who's ready to drink every time someone
只要有人关上冰箱门…
shuts the refrigerator door...
天啊,旁边出现一个人
...and oh, my God, there's a harmless character right behind it?
大家都得喝…
Who's ready to drink every time someone screams the word....
只要有人喊"不要"
No!
刺拉松开始了!
Let's get this Stabathon started!
搞定
Yes.
换我大展身手了
Oh, yeah. Back on my game.
完美
Perfrect.
新工作开始,第一章
New workinprogress, chapter one.
刚搬到伍兹伯勒时…
When l moved to Woodsboro,
我从来没有想到…
l never in a million years dreamed
会再次扮演重要角色
that l would again play the critical role...
并且调查连续杀人案
in solving another series of these....
这是怎么回事?
What the hell?
盖儿,你在哪里?
Gale, where are you?
我跟踪小鬼到刺拉松现场
l followed the kids to the Stabathon.
位于狄伦路上的废弃农场
There's an old abandoned farm on Fort Dillon Road.
听着,我正在监视现场
Listen, l've got it under surveillance, but...
我认为凶手正准备出击!
...l think the killer's about to make his move!
你为何这么肯定?
What makes you so sure?
翻拍是为了超越原作
You do a remake to outdo the original,
是那些小鬼说的
that's what the kids said.
派对的主题是"刺杀"
This party is all about the Stab movies.
拜托!
Come on!
你可以尬多快?
How meta can you get?
你刚说什么?
How "whata" can you get?
不知道,跟小鬼们学的
l don't know. l heard them say it.
杜威,听我说
Dewey, listen to me,
马上过来那里!
you have to get out here!
你负责抓凶手
Come on, you catch the killer, l get the story.
我负责报独家,双赢
lt's a winwin.
我以为你会自己搞定的
Well, l thought you were going rogue, Gale.
你在开玩笑吗?别闹了!
Oh, are you serious? Come on!
算了,谢谢你这么信任我
Forget it. Thanks for having faith in me.
我要修理设备了
l gotta fix my equipment.
盖儿!
Gale!
妈的
Shit.
不错,干得好,我非常感动
Bravo. Very well done. l'm very impressed.
我是说…有一点感动
l mean, kind of impressed. Not really.
- 没错,她很哈我 - 没错…
That'll do. Yeah, she wants me. Yeah. Yeah.
不要!
No!
- 喂? - 喂
Hello? Hello.
- 你是谁? - 你在等电话吗?
Who is this? Were you expecting somebody?
没有
No.
我根本不认识你
You know, l don't even know you...
我已经开始讨厌你了
and l dislike you already.
希克斯,你离狄伦路多远?
Hicks, how far are you from Fort Dillon Road?
- 顶多五分钟,长官 - 开快点
Five minutes at the most, sir. Well, step on it.
看看窗外吧
Look out your window.
盖儿,小心后面!
Gale! Gale, behind you!
盖儿!
Gale.
别动!
Freeze!
别挡路,你们这些智障!
Get out of the way, you morons!
Damn it!
按住伤口
Okay, put pressure on that.
- 抓到他了吗? - 没有
Did you catch him? No.
希望摄影机有拍到
Hopefully your cameras got something.
摄影机不只一个,杜威
They weren't the only ones, Dewey.
什么?
What?
上面藏了一架摄影机
There was a webcam hidden up there.
一直对着我拍
lt was watching me.
网路摄影机?
A webcam?
- 他在拍摄杀人过程 - 什么?
He's recording the murders. What?
这一次…
This time...
他在拍电影
...he's making the movie.
帮席妮看门,真讨厌
Sidney Prescott detail, man. l don't like it.
每次死的都是守卫的警察
The cops guarding the house, they always get it.
你在讲什么?
What are you talking about?
这是电影里的警察规则
lt's a movie cop rule.
最逊的就是演警察
lt sucks to be a cop in a movie,
除非你是布鲁斯威利
unless you're Bruce Willis.
不是每部片的警察都会死
Not all cops die in movies.
没错,但是…
No, but...
如果明天退休,你就会死
if it's your last day before retirement, you do.
如果是菜鸟,发现老婆怀孕了…
lf you're a rookie and just found out your wife is pregnant...
你就会死
you do.
如果拍档比你帅,你就会死
Or if your partner is better looking than you, you do.
顺道一提…
And by the way...
刚才算我赢
l win that one.
我认了,待会换我巡逻
You know what, l'll take the next perimeter.
我马上回来
l'll be right back.
妈的
Shit.
这个我听过
l know this one.
你不该说"马上回来"的
You're not supposed to say that, are you?
新的世代,新的规则
New decade, new rules.
照以前的规则…
You know, these days...
你回来会发现我挂了
...you might come back, find me dead.
眼睛被挖掉,舌头吐出来
Eyes gouged out, tongue sticking out.
总有一个会中
Could go either way.
我得学学新规则
l gotta learn this shit.
我去巡逻了
l'll take this one.
豪斯
Hey, Hoss.
- 小心点 - 我非常谨慎
Be careful. l'm always careful.
命悬一线啊
Dead man walking.
柏金斯,刚才巡逻时…
Perkins, was there a window open
有窗户是开着的吗?
on your last perimeter check?
柏金斯,请回答
Perkins, come in, over.
安东尼?
Anthony?
柏金斯?
Perkins?
该死的
Damn it.
你真该看看你刚才的孬样,菜鸟
You should've seen the look on your face, rookie.
搞什么鬼?
Hoss! What the fuck?
哇靠
Oh, shit.
你在哪?
Where are you?
去他的布鲁斯威利
Fuck Bruce Willis.
抱歉,风铃原本在这里的
Sorry! The wind chimes were over here.
我想试着修好它,抱歉
lt was me. l was trying to fix them, sorry.
我刚从商店回来
l'm just back from the store.
你去买东西?
You're shopping?
这是我解压的管道
My stress buster.
车上还有一袋,我马上回来
l've got one more bag in the car. l'll be right back.
吉儿?你要接吗?
Jill? You gonna get that?
罗伯兹公馆
Roberts residence.
你的命蛮硬的嘛,席妮?
You're a survivor, aren't you, Sidney?
你唯一的专长就是逃命
Your one and only skill. You survive.
我有一个问题
l have one question for you...
如果亲友们全死光了…
...what good's it to be a survivor in this little drama...
就算你能存活又怎样呢?
...if everyone close to you is dead?
- 你是谁? - 转到第六频道
Who are you? Turn on the TV to channel six.
- 你到底是谁? - 开电视看预告吧
Who the fuck are you? Turn it on. Watch the teaser.
在这个死亡之夜…
nearly turned deadly tonight with
凶杀案最新的受害者…
the latest victims of these attacks...
是警长夫人盖儿瑞利
being the wife of the Woodsboro sheriff, Gale Riley...
本名是盖儿魏瑟丝
...AKA Gale Weathers...
被刀刺伤后目前情况危急
...who's in serious condition tonight after being stabbed.
攻击者已经逃离现场…
Her assailant then disappeared in a sea of identical
很高兴你回来,值回票价吧?
Glad you came home, Sidney? Has it been worth it yet?
你为何这样做?
Why are you doing this?
朋友固然重要
Friends count...
但家人才是骨肉相连的,对吧?
...but it's the family ties that cut deep, right?
- 我没说错吧? - 什么意思?
Am l right? What do you mean?
你最在乎的人
The ones you care about most.
有谁比家人还重要?
And what's closer than family?
- 血缘的关系 - 不要
The bond of blood. Don't .
你救不了她们的
You can't save them.
你能做的…只有旁观
All you can do... is watch.
吉儿?
Jill?
"吉儿:快来接我"
Jill: Come pick me up.
"可碧:我马上到"
Kirby: On my way
- 凯特! - 席妮?
Kate! Sid?
吉儿不在房间里
Jill's not in her room. Oh, my God!
我的天啊!
She's gone to Kirby's .
她跑去可碧家了
You gotta call her
快打去叫她回来
and get her back here.
快接,吉儿
Come on, Jill! Leave a message.
她没接电话
She's not picking up.
怎么回事?
What's going on?
杀手打来了,是针对我的
The killer called. He's coming after me...
- 他要先杀我的家人 - 天啊,吉儿
...but he wants my family first. Oh, God, Jill!
我们去叫警察
Let's get the cops.
警察不见了
The cops aren't there. What?
我刚到家时他们都还在
They were there when l first came in,
可是现在不见了
but they're not there now.
我们去可碧家
Let's get to Kirby's .
从前门出去!
Out the front!
把下面顶住!
Brace it from the bottom! Can you?
我们快离开!
Let's get outta here!
凯特,快点!
Kate, come on!
凯特?
Kate?
告诉吉儿我很抱歉
Tell Jill l'm so sorry.
希克斯?你想干嘛?
Hicks? What are you doing?
我看到有人从屋子旁出来
l just saw somebody coming around the side of the house.
豪斯和柏金斯呢?
Where are Hoss and Perkins?
我呼叫他们都没回应
l couldn't get them on the radio.
那是谁的血?
Whose blood is that?
凯特的,我们被攻击了
lt's Kate's . We were just attacked.
- 她死了 - 她在哪里?
She's dead. Where is she?
在前门
Front door.
- 带我过去 - 好
Show me. Okay.
待在这里
Stay here.
我是希克斯警员
This is Deputy Hicks.
罗伯兹家发生凶杀案
l've got a homicide at the Roberts residence.
柏金斯和豪斯没有回覆
No sign of Perkins or Hoss. Copy that. We'll try to locate them.
我很遗憾
l'm so sorry.
你会没事的,好吗?我保证
You're gonna be fine, all right? l swear.
不准再我行我素的
No more " on your own."
我们要永远在一起
lt's you and me, forever.
一、二、三
One, two, three.
温柔点
Easy.
- 杜威? - 怎么了?
Dewey? Yeah?
- 答应我一件事 - 没问题
Promise me something. Anything.
- 逮捕那个王八蛋 - 一定会的
Catch that motherfrucker. Absolutely.
- 我爱你 - 我爱你
l love you. l love you.
你错过好戏了,超级好戏
You missed chaos. Utter chaos.
- 真不敢相信 - 警长夫人出事了!
l can't believe that. The sheriff's wife, man!
她要取消但我们不听,结果呢?
She told us to cancel it and we didn't , and now this?
我们该怎么办?
What are we supposed to do?
罗比,冷静点,这很合理
Robbie, calm down. lt makes sense.
模仿者是这样的
This is what the reboots do.
他们想超越原作
They oneup the original ending.
伍兹伯勒凶杀案在派对中结束
The Woodsboro Murders ended at a party.
所以翻拍版…
So in the remake....
派对并不是真的结局
The party's the false ending.
- 新规则 - 的确是
New rules. Exactly.
好了,各位别介意
Okay, no offense, guys,
我要放"刺杀7"了
but l'm gonna put in Stab 7.
谁都不能破坏我的节庆
Nobody cancels my film festival.
我不想看那个
Whoa, whoa, whoa. l don't wanna watch that,
奥莉薇雅才刚过世
not after what happened to Olivia.
别这样,这是她的最爱
Come on, it was her favorite.
可碧
Wow, Kirby.
- 屌片还蛮多的嘛 - 那当然
You got some classics here. Yup.
坐立不安、威尼斯痴魂
Suspiria, Don't Look Now.
那还用说
You know it.
电影问答我绝对赢,电影儿童
l could trivia your ass under the table, Cinema Boy.
是吗?
Oh, yeah?
第一代的皮面人是谁?
Who played Leatherfrace first?
左纳汉森
Gunnar Hansen. Wow.
你有感觉到吗?
Did you feel that?
刚才有股电流通过我们
That charge that moved between us just then?
那是因为我,我是带电的
Oh, that was me. l have powers.
太性感了
So sexy.
你们太夸张了
You guys are unbelievable.
现在还能玩电影问答?
You're playing fucking trivia games?
条子快来找我们了
The cops are gonna come for us. They're gonna shut down my website.
他们会关闭我的网站
We're so dead!
- 我们死定了! - 我完全同意
Yeah. l agree.
天啊,你从哪蹦出来的?
Jesus Christ, where'd you come from?
前门
The front door.
对了,可碧
By the way, Kirby,
发生了这么多事情
with everything that's going on right now...
千万要记得锁大门
you probably shouldn't leave that unlocked.
抱歉
Sorry.
你到底来这里干嘛?
And may l ask what the hell you're doing here?
什么?续摊不是在这里吗?
What? Didn't l find the afterparty?
你来的是私人派对
No, you found the antiparty
有邀请函才能参加
and it's invitation only.
是啊,我有邀请函
Yeah, well, l got an invitation.
吉儿给的
From Jill.
有什么八卦吗?
So, what's the story?
什么?
What?
你寄了简讯给我
You sent me a text message.
"在可碧家里续摊"
"Afterparty over at Kirby's house."
这是从你手机寄出的
l mean, it was from your phone.
什么叫从我的手机寄出?
What do you mean, from my phone?
我的手机呢?
Where is my phone?
大概掉在你车上,我没传简讯
l think l left it in your car. l didn't text him.
我没传简讯给你
l didn't text you.
我证明给你看
And l'll prove it.
所以…查理、罗比
So, Charlie, Robbie.
间接害人有什么感觉?
How does it feel to be an accessory to a crime?
连警长夫人都敢惹?
l mean, really, Dewey's wife?
我玩完了
My life is over.
谁用吉儿的手机传简讯给我?
So which one of you guys sent me a text message from Jill's phone?
你讲什么我们都得相信吗?
We're just supposed to accept that you're telling the truth?
你的手机不是掉了吗?
lsn't your phone missing?
- 我又买了一支 - 真的?
Got a new one. Really?
还真是迅速
Oh, that's incredibly convenient.
- 杜威,我是希克斯 - 怎么了?
Dewey, it's Hicks. What's up?
凯特罗伯兹死了
Kate Roberts is dead...
席妮逃离现场了
...and Sidney fled the scene.
什么?凯特怎么了?
What? What happened to Kate?
跟其他人一样被刺死了
She was stabbed just like the others.
- 那吉儿呢? - 完全找不到人
What about Jill? No sign of her at all.
豪斯和柏金斯死哪里去了?
Where the hell were Hoss and Perkins?
他们死在两条街外的警车上
They were found dead in their car two blocks away.
身上多处遭到刺伤
Multiple stab wounds.
好吧
Okay.
- 我马上过去 - 是,长官
l'm on my way. Yes, sir.
打错了
Wrong number.
- 谁打来的? - 打错的
Who was that? Nobody.
你有租片子吗?
Did you pick a movie?
有啊,租了恐怖片
Yeah. We're gonna go scary. Saw 4.
"夺魂锯4"
我去电影院看了,逊毙了
Ugh, l saw that in theaters. lt sucks.
完全不恐怖但很恶心
lt's not scary, it's gross.
好吧
All right.
All right...
我是"通行无阻"的罗比
get ready for a Hall Pass with Robbie Mercer extra.
今晚很有可能
Now tonight, there is a good chance...
查理渥克,没错,我的查理渥克
that Charlie Walker, yes, my Charlie Walker...
可能会有艳遇
...may get lucky with a girl.
我不能透露目前的位置
Now l'm unable to divulge my exact location...
不过
however...
我能肯定的是…
suffice it to say...
伍兹伯勒高中
that Woodsboro High
应该会出现在…
may be in store...
宅男历史分类的影片架上
for some geek history.
等着看吧
We'll see.
有人吗?
Hello!
谁在那里?
Who's there?
我的天啊!
Oh, my God!
- 查理? - 干嘛?
Hey, Charlie? Yeah?
抱歉,我知道你很爱电影
l'm sorry. l know you're into the movie and all, but...
不过现在是亲热的好机会
now would be a really good time to make a move.
要由我来主动吗?
For me to make a move?
你不能够主动吗?
Couldn't you make a move?
我刚刚有啊
l just did.
你其实蛮可爱的
'Cause you're actually pretty cute.
特别是当我感到害怕…
Especially when l'm scared...
孤单…
...and lonely...
又喝醉的时候
...and drunk.
你们有看到吉儿进来吗?
Hey, guys, did you see Jill come in?
她不在外面
l didn't see her outside.
是的,崔佛,她在楼上
Yes, Trevor, she is upstairs.
连人都找不到还想保护她
Thank God you're here to protect her when you can't even find her.
外面没有人
There's nobody out here.
各位,我最爱这一段了
Oh, dude, l love this part of the movie.
赞啦…
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
当她们感到安全舒适的时候
Just when you think they're all safe and comfortable in the house...
鬼面杀手就会出来砍人!
Ghostface comes in and bam!
我有打扰到你们吗?
Did l just interrupt something right here?
少来了啦!
Shut the fuck up!
有人邀请你吗,崔佛?
Who invited you, Trevor?
很明显不是你
All right. Clearly not you.
Wow.
我要去楼上笑一下
l'm gonna be upstairs. Laughing.
滚出我家!
Get out of my house!
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
好了,我有点醉了
Okay, l'm a little drunk, so...
所以…这不是网路的问题
...don't blame your internet connection.
来看看查理的进度,好吗?
Let's see what Charlie's up to, shall we?
或是崔佛和吉儿的战绩
Or the saga of Trevor and Jill.
伍兹伯勒高中这么刺激
Oh, the intrigue of Woodsboro High.
这么多故事哪还需要杀手?
Who needs a killer around when there's so much drama?
装反了
Oh, man.
这样就对了
That's better.
等一下,你不能杀我!有规则的!
Wait, no, you can't! You can't! There's rules!
我是gay!我是gay!
l'm gay! l'm gay!
如果有用的话
l mean, if it helps.
可碧!
Kirby!
我找到电话了
l found my phone.
原来在你房间里
lt was up in your room.
根本没人寄简讯给崔佛
There was no text message sent to Trevor.
他真爱骗人
He is such a liar.
他去哪了?
Where is he?
什么叫他去哪了?
What do you mean, where is he?
他刚刚才去楼上找你
He just went upstairs looking for you.
他不在楼上
He's not upstairs.
崔佛?
Trevor?
查理?罗比?
Charlie? Robbie?
他们大概在外面
Maybe they're outside.
吉儿!
Jill!
席妮!
Sidney!
抱歉,我应该跟你说的
l'm sorry, l should've told you.
没关系
No, it's okay.
我要你马上跟我走,好吗?
l need you to come with me right now, okay?
- 快逃! - 罗比!
Run! -Robbie!
走!
Go!
席妮!
Sidney!
快点!
Come on!
- 到阳台上! - 没别的路走吗?
The balcony! There's no other way out?
我们跳下去!
We can jump!
这里是二楼!
lt's two stories!
- 你的手机呢? - 在这
Where's your cell? -Here.
- 躲到床底下! - 什么?
Get under the bed! -What? Just do it! Get under the bed...
快躲到床底下…
...and don't make a sound
别出声也别出来
and don't come out
除非我叫你,懂吗?
until l come get you, okay?
相信我
Trust me.
可以吗?没事吧?
You got it? You're okay?
吉儿,快跑!
Jill, run!
不要停下来,去找救兵
Just keep running, get help!
- 喂? - 杜威!
Hello? Dewey! Sidney, where are you?
席妮,你在哪里?
l'm at Kirby's .
我在可碧家
The killer is here. l need your help.
- 杀手在这,赶快来 - 我马上去
l'm on my way. Okay.
席妮!
Sidney? Sidney!
全员赶往私语街329号
l need all units to 329 Whispering Lane.
全员赶往私语街329号!
All units, 329 Whispering Lane!
抱歉,是我
Sorry, it's just me.
我试着报警,但市话断讯了
Look, l tried to call 91 1 , but the landline's dead...
路由器也被砸烂了
and someone smashed the router.
可以用我的手机
l think l got through on my cell.
吉儿呢?
Where's Jill?
天啊!快跑…
Oh, God! Go, go, go!
楼下有个房间
There's a room down here.
我们可以把门反锁
We can lock ourselves in.
我听到你对吉儿喊话
l heard you yelling to Jill.
她逃走了吗?
Did she get away?
我想她应该很安全
l think she's safe.
可碧,让我进去!
Kirby, let me in!
查理
Charlie.
不…我找到罗比了
No, no, no! l just found Robbie.
这是他的血,拜托!
This is his blood. Please!
拜托!有人在外面!
Please! There is someone else out here!
让我进去!
Let me in!
如果不相信他,就别开门
lf you can't trust him, don't open the door.
天啊,让我进去!
My God, let me in!
别靠近门,查理
Get away from the door, Charlie.
可碧,是我,拜托让我进去!
Kirby, it is me. Please let me in!
- 别靠近门,查理 - 是我!
lt's me! Get away from the door, Charlie.
抱歉,我办不到
l'm sorry, l can't .
- 搞什么鬼? - 很抱歉
What the fuck?! l'm sorry.
小心!
Look out!
不要…
No! No, no, no, no!
可碧
Kirby!
天啊,不要,求求你
Oh, God, no, please.
别伤害他!
Leave him alone!
是查理的电话
lt's Charlie's phone.
告诉席妮她今晚死定了
Tell Sidney heads are gonna roll tonight.
告诉她一切都是她害的
Tell Sidney it's all because of her.
或许她愿意和他交换
Or maybe she wants to take his place.
我保证下手干净俐落
l promise to be quick.
是他
lt's him.
好,我去找吉儿
Okay, l'm gonna get Jill.
我们应该聚集在一起
We should be in the same place.
继续跟他说
Just keep him on the phone.
我马上回来,好吗?
l'll be right back, okay?
求求你放他走
Let him go, please.
听说你很爱恐怖片,可碧
l hear you like horror movies, Kirby.
但你有像他一样爱吗?
But do you like them as much as him?
不必看"刺杀"了
Forget watching Stab.
你可以亲自体验
You get to live it.
不…他才是专家!我不是!
No, no, no! He's the expert! lt's not me!
暖身题
Warmup question...
- 杰森的武器? - 开山刀
...Jason's weapon? lt's a machete.
看吧?你确实很懂
There, you see? You do know the genre.
- 麦可迈尔斯? - 屠宰刀
Michael Myers? Butcher knife. Leatherfrace?
- 皮面人? - 电锯,别再问了!
A chainsaw. Please!
不懂的就问席妮
Just ask Sidney if you need some help.
佛莱迪克鲁格?
Freddy Krueger?
刀爪手套
Razor hands.
哪部片引起杀人片风潮…
Name the movie that started the slasher craze.
月光光心慌慌、德州电锯杀人狂
Halloween, Texas Chainsaw Massacre,
左边最后那栋房子,还是惊魂记?
Last House on the Left, or Psycho?
- 惊魂记 - 以上皆非!
Psycho! None of the above!
是1960年的偷窥狂
Peeping Tom, 1960,
由麦可鲍威尔执导
directed by Michael Powell.
第一部以杀手观点来拍的电影
First movie to ever put the audience in the killer's POV.
什么?等等,不行…
What? Wait. No, no, no.
拜托再问我一个问题!
Please, just ask me one more question!
一个就好!
Just one more!
好吧,可碧
All right, Kirby.
这是你最后一次机会
Then it's time for your last chance question.
哪部电影翻拍自恐怖经典…
Name the remake of the groundbreaking horror movie in which
月光光心慌慌、德州电锯杀人狂
Halloween, Texas Chainsaw...
活人生吃、魔山、阴宅
Dawn Of The Dead, The Hills Have Eyes, Amityville Horror...
左边最后那栋房子、十三号星期五
Last House On The Left, Friday The 13th...
半夜鬼上床、血腥情人节
A Nightmare On Elm Street, My Bloody Valentine,
夺命电话、舞夜惊魂、绝命圣诞夜
When A Stranger Calls... Prom Night,
恐怖蜡像馆、鬼雾、食人鱼
Piranha! Black Christmas, House Of Wax, The Fog...
是其中一部,对吧?
lt's one of those, right?
对吧?
Right?
我猜对了
l got it right.
我他妈的猜对了!
l was fucking right!
吉儿?
Jill?
我赢了,查理
l won, Charlie!
我他妈的赢了!
l fucking won!
我赢了,他想打败我
l won. He tried to beat me,
但是我他妈的赢了
but l fucking won.
快好了,再忍一下
Almost there. Just hang tight.
好了,没事了
Okay. Okay. All right.
可碧,这才叫做主动
Kirby, this is making a move.
同班了四年
Four years of classes together
你现在才注意到我?
and you notice me now?
臭婊子!一切都太迟了!
Stupid bitch! lt's too late!
我知道…
l know, l know.
没关系,慢慢来
lt's okay. Take your time.
你不会像电影里死得那么快
Doesn't happen as fast as it does in the movies, l know.
查理…
Charlie.
可碧?
Kirby?
重复看电影可以学不少东西
You know, you learn a lot when you watch movies over and over...
所有的计谋都是为了杀你
and all the plots are about trying to kill you.
- 吉儿呢? - 你以为她逃得了吗?
Where's Jill? You think she's gonna get away?
你以为有人能逃得了吗?
You think anyone gets away?
吉儿
Jill.
你好,席妮
Hello, Sidney.
很惊讶吧?
Surprised?
你看
Watch this.
表姊,只有这一段…
This is the part, my dear cousin, when the cameras...
是不会拍下来的
turn off.
- 查理? - 都处理好了
Charlie? Already taken care of.
杀罗比的那段拍的很棒
Man, l got great footage of my Robbie kill.
比珍妮、玛妮和奥莉薇雅的都好
Better than Jenny and Marnie or Olivia even.
很好,晚点剪接就上传
Good. We'll cut and upload it later
让警察追踪到崔佛那
and make it all traceable to Trevor.
讲到这个
Speaking of which....
有没有回想起什么?
Remind you of anything?
- 吉儿,求求你! - 闭嘴!
Jill, please! Shut up! Dick.
这一切都是跟你学的
Everything l learned l learned from you.
你认为你的前男友很烂吗?
You think you had a shitty boyfriend, Sidney?
这边有个上过就甩的人
Here's one that fucks you, dumps you...
而且还不能让你出名
...and doesn't even make you famous.
干嘛这样,吉儿?我爱你!
What the fuck, Jill? l loved you!
快给我闭嘴!
Shut the fuck up already!
那些条子送你的礼物
l'm sure those cops want you to have this, Jill.
让你防身
For your protection.
求求你!
No!
Please!
你不应该杀光那些人的
Shouldn't have killed all these people, Trev.
甚至还拍成了影片
Gone and put it on video even.
不过还真谢谢你的帮忙
But it means a lot that you did it for me.
你在讲什么东西啊?
What the fuck are you talking about?!
我不再是被你劈腿的女孩
l am not the girl you cheat on.
我全部都办妥了
l've gone through everything.
时间安排的刚刚好
We're definitely good on timeline.
对,太完美了
Oh, yeah. We're perfrect.
不…求求你!
No, no, please!
你现在感觉如何?
Ready for act three?
都搞懂了吗,席妮?
Got it figured out yet, Sidney?
为了维持翻拍的主轴
ln keeping with our remake theme...
这一代的比利鲁米斯由崔佛取代
Trevor's this generation's Billy Loomis
而我们成了无辜的受害者
and we're the innocent victims,
席妮和兰迪
Sidney and Randy.
因为你,全世界才能知道真相
See, with you, the world just heard about what happened.
可是因为我们…
But with us...
大家才能目睹
they're gonna see it.
这将会轰动全世界
lt's gonna be a worldwide sensation.
大家都会看到这部作品
l mean, people gotta see this shit.
现代人不再看书了
lt's not like anyone reads anymore.
我们会享有极高的知名度
We're gonna know fame like you never even dreamed of.
幸存的两个年轻人
Last two teenagers standing.
这次的兰迪会得到美女
This time Randy gets the girl.
你美极了
You were amazing.
你是最合适的受害者
You're the perfrect victim.
我今天的演技很棒吧?
l was so believable today, wasn't l? l mean,
我蒙骗了好多人
l told so many lies
连我自己都快要信以为真了
that l actually started to believe them.
我应该是个天生的骗子
l really think that l was born for this.
你怎么下得了手?
How could you do this?
你知道生在这个家所受的苦吗?
Do you know what it was like growing up in this family?
当你亲戚的痛苦?
Related to you?
人人都是席妮这个,席妮那个的
l mean, all l ever heard was Sidney this and Sidney that...
全都是席妮…
...and Sidney, Sidney, Sidney.
你永远是最出名的那个
You were always just so fucking special!
现在最出名的是我了
Well, now l'm the special one.
你会失手,一定会的
You'll slip. They always do.
来吧,查理,做个了结吧
Come on, Charlie, let's get on with this.
你要坚强一点
You have to be strong.
站稳点,懂吗?
And hold still. Okay?
对…老套了,就像比利和史都
Yeah. Yeah, old school, like Billy and Stu.
来吧,宝贝,刺过来吧
Come on, baby, get it up!
刺我的肩膀…
Shoulder me!
刺过来吧!
Get it up!
这跟排演的不一样
That's not the way we rehearsed it.
你说要像比利和史都
You said it, Charlie. Billy and Stu...
就是崔佛和你
...Trevor, and you.
媒体最喜欢的…
What the media really loves, baby...
是唯一的幸存者
...is a sole survivor.
你问席妮就知道了
Just ask you know who.
崔佛是你的拍档
Trevor was your partner.
但是你…
But you...
你才是幕后主脑
...you were the idea man.
你连朋友都杀了
Even your friends.
我的朋友?
My friends?
你是外星来的吗?
What world are you living in?
我不需要朋友
l don't need friends.
我只要粉丝
l need fans.
你还搞不懂吗?
Don't you get it?
目的并不是杀你
This has never been about killing you.
而是要成为你
lt's about...becoming you.
这个牺牲可大了
l mean, for fuck's sake,
连亲生母亲都杀死了
my own mother had to die,
没什么大不了的
no great loss there,
这样才能忠于原作
so l could stay true to the original.
很变态吧?
That's sick, right?
变态是个新说法
Well, sick is the new sane.
你成名过了,现在换我成名了
You had your 15 minutes, now l want mine!
不然我以后该怎样?
l mean, what am l supposed to do?
去上大学吗?
Go to college?
念硕士班?找工作?
Grad school? Work?
看看四周,我们身在人群中
Look around. We all live in public now,
我们都在网路上
we're all on the lnternet.
你以为现代人是怎么出名的?
How do you think people become famous anymore?
你根本不需要有成就
You don't have to achieve anything.
只要周遭发生怪事就行了
You just gotta have fuckedup shit happen to you.
所以你还是得死,席妮
So, you do have to die, Sid.
规则就是如此
Those are the rules.
新的电影,新的系列
New movie, new franchise.
主角只要一个就够了
There's only room for one lead, and let's face it,
老实说,你也不再是纯真少女了
your ingenue days... they're over.
别告诉我你没预料到这天
Don't tell me you didn't know this day would come.
妈的!
Fuck!
快点,动作快点!
Come on, let's move it
检查两侧的房间和楼上
Check the rooms, both sides and upstairs. Yes, ma'am.
吉儿,请叙述一下
Jill, can you give us a description of the murderer?
吉儿,成为英雄的感觉如何?
Jill, how does it feel to be a hero?
"伍兹伯勒社区医院"
吉儿,你没事了
Jill. You made it.
这才是最重要的
That's all that matters.
崔佛和查理试图谋杀我
Trevor, Charlie, they tried to kill me.
听说他们杀了我妈
And l heard they killed my mom.
还有罗比和可碧
And Robbie and Kirby, too.
先躺着
Just lay back.
休息一下
Try to rest.
你太太她…
ls your wife....?
她没事的,正在复元中
She's gonna be fine. She's recovering.
如果我要出书的话
lf l ever write a book one day, l'd ...
一定会找她一起写
...l'd want her to write it with me.
我们会是好伙伴
We'd be a good team with our...
连受伤的地方都一样
...matching wounds and all.
我们是幸存者
We're survivors now.
真希望席妮没有死
l just wish Sidney was, too.
吉儿
Jill...
他们还不敢断论
...they're not sure yet.
她仍然有生命危险
lt's still touch and go...
不过她在加护病房
...but she's in lCU.
医生认为席妮有可能存活
And they think Sidney just might make it.
什么?
What?
但我见到崔佛杀了她
But l saw Trevor kill her.
我们还不能确定
Look, we don't know yet.
但她还在和死神搏斗
But she's hanging on.
我想见她
l wanna see her.
她还没醒来
She's not awake yet.
她可能会失去记忆
And she may not remember anything.
你得协助她恢复记忆
You'll to help her with that.
多的是时间
All in time.
现在先休息,好吗?
Just get some rest now, okay?
她不会有事吧?
She gonna be okay?
不会
Yeah.
- 这孩子真坚强 - 她必须要坚强
She's a strong kid. She's gonna have to be.
她还问你有没有事
She asked if you were okay.
她说你们应该合作出书
She thinks you guys should write a book together...
连伤的地方都一样
with your matching wounds.
为何?她伤到肩膀?
Why, she was stabbed in the shoulder?
她怎么知道我也是?
How did she know l was, too?
糟了!
Shit!
你就是死不了,是吗?
You just won't die, will you?
你是谁?麦可迈尔斯吗?
Who are you? Michael fucking Myers?
我可不这么认为
Yeah, l don't think so.
快去死吧!
Fucking die already!
伤口缝得如何?
How are those stitches
席妮!
希克斯,去席妮的病房
Hicks, get to Sidney Prescott's room and call for backup!
- 马上请求支援! - 马上办,长官!
Be right up, sir!
席妮!
Sindey!
杜威!
Sid! -Dewey!
这就是结局吗,席妮?
ls this how it's gonna be, Sid?
电影的结局应该在屋子里
The ending of the movie was supposed to be at the house.
这真是蠢毙了
l mean, this is just silly.
就当作是另一种结局吧
Consider this an alternate ending.
你永远都逃不了的,吉儿
You're never gonna get out of this, Jill.
- 我当然可以 - 杜威!
Of course l will. Dewey!
冷静点…
Easy. Okay, okay.
- 书怎么办? - 看来我得自己写了
What about the book? Looks like l'll just have to write it myself.
该死的!
Goddamn it!
别想给我开枪
Don't even think about shooting...
否则我打爆杜威的头
...or l'll blow Dewey's head off.
怎样?你认为我不敢吗?
What? You think l won't do it?
把枪给我!
Give me your gun!
快点!
Do it!
把枪给我
You just had to be the hero, huh? Gimme your gun.
你是聋子吗?
What are you, deaf?
把枪给我!
Give me your gun!
站起来
Now get up.
把手放在头上
Keep your hands over your head.
千万别做傻事
Don't do anything stupid
别他妈的指使我
Don't fucking tell me what to do.
天啊
Oh, God.
- 起来,臭婊子 - 好
Now get up, bitch. Okay.
起来!快点!
Now! Get up.
快点
Come on.
走过来
Let's go!
给我滚过来
Get your skinny ass out here.
好
Okay.
让我好好享受打爆你头的快感
l'm gonna enjoy blowing your head off.
- 我可以说句遗言吗? - 什么?
Okay, but... can l just... have one final word?
你想说的是"饶命"吗?
What? " Please" ?
不是,是…
No.
"净空"
Clear. "Clear" ?
- 净空? - 净空
Clear.
你忘了翻拍的规则了
You forgot the first rule of remakes, Jill.
千万别招惹原作
Don't fuck with the original.
天啊,杜威
Oh, my God, Dewey.
- 我被什么打了? - 别问了
What hit me? Don't ask.
你还好吗?
You okay?
她是从后面攻击的
She was standing right behind me.
这是老套了
They always are.
Oh, God.
射得好
Nice one.
希克斯,你没死?
Hicks? You're alive?
防弹衣,防嗝屁
Wear the vest... save your chest.
有两名员警受伤
We got two officers down.
多名伤者
Several injuries.
还有一名新嫌犯
And a new suspect.
快叫医生来,该死的!
We need a doctor, goddamn it!
我不知道你怎样
l don't know about you,
不过我的心情很好
but l feel a whole lot better.
我们在伍兹伯勒社区医院等候
We're live at Woodsboro Community Hospital...
首次公开发言的幸存者吉儿罗伯兹
awaiting a first public statement from Jill Roberts, survivor.
她是新版伍兹伯勒凶杀案的幸存者
a survivor of what is now being called the Woodsboro Massacre Reboot.
吉儿罗伯兹这个名字
Jill Roberts is her name,
将在全世界造成轰动
a name the whole world will now know.
她独自一人
who singlehandedly put a stop...
结束了21世纪的重大杀人案
to this 21st century Woodsboro killing spree.
伍兹伯勒的吉儿罗伯兹
Jill Roberts of Woodsboro...
今晚安抚了大家的心灵
a girl who's lifted all our spirits tonight.
就像是电影里的美国英雄
An American hero, right out of the movies.